ILGWU. Mid-West Region audio-visual materials 5780/101 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Mid-West Region audio-visual materials
1988-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/101 AV
1.22 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Audio-visual material.
This collection contains audio-visual material that was either produced by or featured the ILGWU. Included are videos from ILGWU conventions and videos about the garment industry in the United States.
6849751
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, May 29, 2013
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
From its earliest years, the ILGWU was involved in organizing women's garment workers in Chicago, and efforts to gain members in the city and throughout the Midwest continued throughout the union's existence. The Midwest Region represented workers in Chicago and much of Illinois, Indiana, Wisconsin, Michigan, and Iowa.
Morris Bialis was the ILGWU's longtime representative in the Midwest, Manager of the Chicago Joint Board, and the Midwest Region Director from 1922 to 1976. Harold Schwartz served as regional director from 1976 to 1978. Schwartz was succeeded by Lou Montenegro, who held the post until his retirement in 1990. Stanley Gross was Midwest Region Director at the time of the ILGWU's merger with ACTWU in 1995.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of VHS tapes produced or featuring the ILGWU. Many of the video recordings contain newscast segments, particularly when the ILGWU or someone from the union appeared on the nightly news. There are also political videos and recordings of conventions, union appeared on the nightly news.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/101: ILGWU. Mid-West Region records
Women's clothing industry -- United States.; Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- United States.; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- Midwest Region.
6849751
- What Happened to the American Dream? Political Action Video (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  VHS. 2 copies. Running time: 10:30.
- Jay Mazur/Rain Fair, Evening News (CBS), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  VHS. Running time: 3:25. November 24, 1991.
- UNITE Convention Highlights, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  VHS
- NY is Fashion, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  VHS. Ruth Glanz Productions, ILGWU. August 1992.
- The True Cost of NAFTA, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Convention Dues Debate, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- [No title] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  VHS. Includes note from Burt King to Stanley Crap
- ILGWU Department of Labor Hall of Fame, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union: Its About Jobs (Box 1, Folder 9)
- McNeill-Lehrer Report; Industrial Homework: Debate with Sue Cowell, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  VHS. Running time: 8:00. December 19, 1988.
- Cope Senate Group Video, Illinois State AFL-CIO. Sen. Paul Simon, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  VHS. Running time: 10:08. September 21, 1990.
- ILGWU - UNITE AND FIGHT (Box 1, Folder 12)
  VHS. 2 copies.
- Chicago Federation of Labor (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "We do the Work, Serving Our Future" (Box 1, Folder 14)
  VHS. Running time: 16:00
- Carol Mosley Brawn, Braun for U.S. Senate (Box 1, Folder 15)
  VHS. Coffee Video. Running time: 13:30
- Secretary of State Literacy Office, Illinois State Library. On the Job; Workplace Literacy and WLS News Story (Box 1, Folder 16)
  VHS. Running time: 20:34
- Convention of Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees, AFL-CIO, CLC, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Health Care, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  VHS. Paula Green Advertising, ILGWU, YGWO186: 30. March 18, 1994.
- ILGWU, Apparel Jobs Abroad (Box 1, Folder 19)
  VHS. September 27, 1992.
- UNITE, Words: UN96-107, FACE UN96-109, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  VHS. Running time: :60. January 25, 1996.
- ILGWU, Apparel Job and Maidenform, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- [No title] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Side A- No Description; Side B- InJu: Julio Cesar Guevrero & Jose Santos MTZ. Audiocassette
- Tecora: Gospel/Labor Music, The tie that binds (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Audiocassette